outside credibly incredibly true know
why let me tell you what in a hydroponic
campus you are here in the beginning
cause I saw broken down you wanna come
Sun ep
alright I'm gonna like it askew together
I'll just lie in front of me thanks very
much I'm sick people dog food gentleman
welcomes you and here before me to break
it up premise 1 everything observable
biology it's a good look I heard I was
standing there the whole time I have all
day so everything observer rally it
depends upon something yeah number two
the universe is observable reality
therefore number is yeah ok so somehow
lied about some of gravity some of
everything everything can be like
anything that you can accomplish is
going to be into I guess you're not
going to get one thing slows from
another yeah yeah yeah agree Thank You
universe
I want saying it okay number one
everything in the physical subject but
the to the universe observable be there
for number three the universe wants to
Pendleton I understand you I understand
to Dragon school I simply disagree with
it okay now what you said which is that
universe eternal the terms of time
because the terminology that's difficult
issue study universe for which is my my
deduction has been nothing to utilize
the universe could very well be here for
all who everyone what still must depend
upon the why why not
wrong here is that Angus a mass
therefore you must have a reason why you
say much dependent on figures for me to
generate by that much you very much know
what you have to do is you have to tell
me why my premise one is wrong or why my
premise two as well series I'm do you
know I'm not a no no no I've got your
your basic premise of one thing flows
from another not having everything is a
lid that or that which went before it
and at the tree of the three depends on
the ground
the rain and the Sun and the oil
strawberry I'm not using the Kalam
cosmological argument here I'm not talk
about before having this time I was that
cool right at the end
if I might just tell me where I'm going
wrong maybe every time yes so you're
saying that everything depends on
something else and so what we see right
now other thing after everything in
observable reality yeah okay everything
that we can which is empirically then
yeah that's for whatever maybe that is
dependent upon something okay
the universe was in the epochal realm
for computing such expensive debts are
some of it yes therefore the universe
are many aspects of the universal which
we have as yet no idea the science has
no idea and that's well there is a most
of the universe which is beyond the
realm of our senses beyond the realm of
observability right so people if I
perceive about the ocean absolutely I'm
not postulating that we should have to
go all the elements of something in
order for us to to know the full thing
I'm saying using an adductor muscle here
okay the Constitution yeah but this
requires assumptions right unless you
have all information if you're using any
inductive method you are making
assumptions reasonable rational
assumption perhaps and nevertheless
function I'm sure those of it yeah
absolutely but I'm just saying that
doesn't make it so
that doesn't make it much that makes it
an appeal is also I'm saying
good job any deduction invitations
anybody that claim any argument foot
forward rest on a premise that you smart
with right and then well actually all
you end up doing is going around in a
big circle improving the premise what
you have to do the time why you just
managed to do both of you can maybe have
a little tube in a tooth you talk is you
have to tell me why from is a promise be
is wrong okay so in an eternal universe
which has no beginning and has no end
yet it is its own thing it is its own
continuation your and therefore does not
depend on anything it always was there
for how can it depend on any other
question the answer if I had to that
everything in the beginning everything
that begins to exist has a cause
and the universe began to exhibit the
better-known eternal University began to
existence are eternal if conditional if
I had such you did yes then in that case
you could come back to this day what
what the universe didn't begin to
correct it
I'm not saying that I'm saying that it
did begin through this beginning time is
relative you say the universe had a
start and therefore the universe has a
home of depend on something and Allah is
the thing the universe depends on right
now I get where you're going or my
judgment on this by the way when people
see swarm an argument they start to
preach lism he like okay this man is
trying to get away from the ugly
I'm thank you I love you open my supply
brother I am I am so I know that and I
got nothing but love for you and
everyone else
okay let's just use our rational
faculties different people okay the
universe it's an observable reality
everything was instinct thing applies
accordingly
no I'm saying you can realize this
number wise using in touch number two to
make another argument which is refers to
implausibly of the article contingencies
let me pursue yeah everything that is
contingency is really like dependency
yeah the universe has anything that has
an explanation or an of itself
yeah or is necessarily true or just
country doesn't require something
external in order to explain the
universe so requires something external
in order to explain it because it's
contingently true I just want to say if
you believe it is a finite thing I agree
with you but knowledge can leave it to
be an eternal of it it is its own
explanation I'm telling you I'm telling
you that this position I suggest is
that's it that's it it just is what is
the universe it's just it's or Bertrand
Russell cylinder debate in 1930 and I
know I know that philosophically and
didactically this is an unsatisfying
response because there's nowhere to go
after that right
but that but that protect it just is
well I'm poor it's or is truth no no
it's not true let me tell you can't you
say that if you're working on this used
or what's richest expressing opinions
right let's bring because they you
disagree then I'll say it is not true
you can say it's not suited to you we'll
stop everyone I'm sorry to be like man
that's ok on ok let me do that again
you're working in this club to see you
walk in the desert yeah and you see your
life phone and go I'll find that out
later but now we've got microphones
above again anyways listen now we get
more professional guys coming anyway the
point is if you saw that you're not
going to say I'm sorry you're not going
to say this phone just is no human being
would do that you would try and find an
explanation for the phone your rational
faculties would lead you to find out the
phone had a contingent its contingent on
something else be and also going to
contingent explanation yeah yeah what
forget it I understand necessarily in
above itself
you must be clean from an external
reality this is one you the element of
the universe is not the whole bit this
is not the whole thing yeah the universe
created the phone the universe is the
end of the story yeah in some way or
other the contents of the universe came
about to create that phone right the
atoms and the people and the Eagle
issues of the earth that created the
people and the atoms that were created
in stars came together to make that
phone right in a very long convoluted
and complex process over billions of
years right bang cotton was created by
the universe yeah so my agents would
give a bit of wait how are those aliens
created by the universe itself right
ultimately the universe's will be
ultimately oxygen incredibly incredibly
in trouble no why let me tell you I know
yes I know we're interested because now
you've given the universe and
intelligent capacitors wait a minute
we're X sorry hold the holder holder
over
the universe is a single consciousness
evolving yeah experiencing itself
through millions of different eyes of
which each of us is one we are all one
consciousness than me the resides inside
of you is the same as the me that
resides inside of me right we are all
one consciousness experiencing itself
subjectively from a billion different
perspective a trillion different
projection every and every tree every
single one of these things is conscious
and aware the universe as a whole is
conscious and aware women it is a
creative force that's what the universe
is get other rounds of created for
supporting us in an expression it sounds
a bit spiritual to me
Hey really hey may I say something to my
friends like that doesn't sound true
sure that sounds religiously no
spiritual no religion is a thing as a
man used to enslave and control and
divide people to set them against each
other
Muslim against addiction against you you
not i mean this has been done for
thousands of years divide and rule and
all that all religion is divide and rule
Thailand was a religious man having said
that I want to ask your pride and ruins
of tactic religion is one anthemic to
back tack allow happy blacks and white
is another one how you've said that red
and blue is another one we all mean is a
billionaire out there let's have a
conversation
now I'm going to say to you this Judas
said first of all the universe has
created Republican personifying the
universe personifying the universe
giving the inanimate the characteristics
of human
anthropomorphizing matters now no one
knows me know some human I got holidays
all alone hold up this you said the
universe created the phone correct means
to say in your mind that you believe as
you've just made a case for it you
actually believe there is a metaphysical
reality within the universe which is a
consciousness correct correct which
allows for things to be create single
universal binding consciousness the
hansoms means everything justify what
you still planted with you why do I need
to justify higher typically right okay
let me I'm expressing a belief justify
allow scientifically do you not I mean
I'm expression with the lead
I think major I believe this in my hair
in my hair or in ordinary I'm going to
have to pull you up on that we don't
believe a lies in the universe we don't
believe that we don't believe a lies
inside the universe with us we don't
believe in that allows omnipresent don't
believe that therefore science which is
a tool which is analyzing that which is
a universe - exactly right very much we
use thank instrumentally to come to
conclusions about that which we feel
sense whatsoever yeah
so may I just marriages okay okay please
allow it yeah now what I'm saying is
science is applicable it's actually
completely applicable in what you're
saying and it's completely not
applicable when it comes to a lot
therefore what you have to do since
Allah is not in the universe okay
is you have to justify to me how
scientifically what evidences you have
scientifically that the universe has a
positive spring and it's a length you're
actually inventing your own religion
today hey may I want away from the I'm
not inventor but you know I am
absolutely not inventing a man or not
what I'm trying okay this is not me I
did not come up with these ideas this is
doing it up what do you mean who made it
up there's what I'm sort what I'm
talking about the sort of Buddhist
Terrace I guess kind of kind of
philosophy yeah where where the ultimate
reality is consciousness and you can
access that ultimate reality through
meditation you know power plants these
kinds of things you know stream and
exhibitions all over the world have been
doing these things for thousands of
years right anyway so you ask you ask
you to say a couple of things about
clients right so let me let me do so
yeah so first of all I like what you
said about tie into the tool that is
exactly what it is
science is a tool which allows us to
discover in a limited way how things
work so that we can manipulate our
environment to make our lives better
right this is how we came up with
technology because how we made tools
right with my understanding the physical
world around us and working out ways to
manipulate it to our advantage right
this is what science is all about
science is not a pathway to truth it's a
pathway to discovering falsehood but it
is not uncovered truth science by its
very nature I am a scientist by training
so it's quite very nature seeks to
disprove things right to refine the
approximation
so I've never claims to come up with
perfect ultimate answers to anything
right
it seats to refine and get a better
approximation always right and therefore
and what our group science can never be
used to justify ultimate truth right you
can will never analyze it scientifically
it doesn't work like that
ultimately it's felt in your heart and
in your soul and in your conscience
right that is where truth resides now is
not reside out there it resides in here
now and any truth that does not have at
its heart Brotherhood companions women
collaboration friendship we're all on
the same planet at the same time for a
very very short life I would relate to
make the most of it economically claim
before we bring the emotional argument
let's stick to the logic you just said
here that fight is not a pathway to an
epistemological ultimately very angry
with you
Tony agree good having said that we move
forward we're number two you said within
our consciousness you don't believe in
God do you know how do you account for
consciousness consciousness is what you
would call God what people would call
God is what I would call the universal
consciousness but if you're not a
creator in the sense that it made us as
something special in it own image off
yeah and that we somehow have dominion
over the rest of our us is bullshit why
is it okay why he does it with
instructed acceptance against each other
and accept us against the nature the
splitting is not on how any creature is
supposed to live against their
environment leave out the emotion leave
out how can you leave out and most where
emotional things you can't leave it no I
get climate-related in check a little
bit maybe yeah but you can't control
them you'll what legal now I mean to say
is that here we're trying to focus on a
logical argument if you just start
blowing out your subjective opinions I'm
going to be quite ridiculous but I
thought saying oh you know this is like
telling you think of the plan moral
things you say what kind of man is just
he's not engaging with you a rational
level
so you have to kind of respect economy
number one number two I'm saying - I
agree with you I agree with you so much
is what you're saying is a fine cigar a
means and ultimately number two what you
said is consciousness I'll ask you a
question consciousness which is really
an inbuilt thing which cannot be proven
scientifically cannot be proven or touch
scientifically and by the way science
can never prove consciousness because
it's out of the reach of the empirical
five senses or the five senses generally
therefore I'm asking you a question why
do you believe in consciousness and how
do you justify your belief or another
belief consciousness is a reality it's
not a question why are we are aware
therefore we are consciousness therefore
conscious is real are we at that that's
pretty much an axiom that you can your
honor mean we're here talking we're
aware therefore we are conscious
therefore consciousness be fit let me
let me put some really almost a
Descartes kind of argument isn't it I
think I have almost normalizer but I'm
going I'm going to put this to them if
that's the case then I could say look I
believe in God
yeah for me self-evident that's how it's
that's fine okay that way mine that way
for because what is if you think about
really think about them hopefully you
are actually really interesting
conversation as a wife because you admit
that science cannot give you objective
reality and in a full way yeah we'll say
that objective realities of piping
there's no such thank you very much
are you possible in this coming am i
what what one me I don't know they I
learn anything is I'm just me some
fucking pissed I apologize but there's a
pigeonholing of everything it's just
sickness in our satellite everyone wants
to label you okay but hold on even if
you say that that's the case look on
your world view there's no way of
proving or disproving the sickness no so
what I don't feel a need to I'm quite
happy living as I live and letting
others live as they want to live and in
your unlock down here trying to convince
anyone I don't even go I'm not doing
it's not like anyone I've ever put us
with it you don't believe in go not in
no not in the judeo-christian Muslim
kind of way now don't believe a hug I'm
going to make sure that before I leave
in about will leave in three minutes to
rattle we're not going to convert me I'm
over you
you know there another character looked
it I'm gonna make sure no no I'm going
to make sure hyper and you're going to
fall into options you're going to fall
into a massive logical fallacy or you
can agree with me that God exists unlike
you today now it's doing I have a
girlfriend Emily you're saying objective
reality objective reality or cannot
really or science cannot need your
subjects president that's the empirical
world there is no such thing as
objective reality there is only ever
subjective reality therefore for me if I
like just for me yeah therefore it is
real for you and that's all that matters
to you and that means with this
objective is more in your mind is higher
data retroactively much that must mean a
largest no it means that I exist to you
okay but that's for me that's all I need
exactly
exactly how do you wear in stressful
agreement right okay we're in totally
because with that because you have
understand something yeah I'm happy with
it if you saying that Elijah's will move
beyond me yeah yeah and that the
subjective experience is higher than the
objective experience therefore you know
I don't know exactly foods there is only
subject because I'm not saying at high
I'm saying sex between Stephanie hold on
you're saying but then objectivity
doesn't exist yeah I know we have a word
in the language of actually objectivity
through objectivity is impossible you
always have biases pre people are given
to you so I can good ticket I'm just
gonna finish off on saying I think
limiting using therefore if your
subjective because you don't even know
if I'm here or not well you're here to
me sorry you don't know if I'm here
you're here to me okay good I just you
correct okay click on open why I'm
saying is therefore if I come along and
say God exists yeah that's my subjective
because we are that's better then you
say that higher for you
then you saying to me you did know but
it's not nice inject me so I have the
only only experience it matters to me is
microfiber
as the only experience of magic user
experience so an airport ala is utterly
wheel to you and utterly not really
human and they were saying all buddy
uses does it feel cool I'm gonna coming
take all the signal coming there's a
treatment for it anyways activate you
ask it you're asking question we get
right to the heart of quantum mechanics
is very very very big question some of
doing it believes that things do happen
whether we're doing no they don't know
they go to the principle world it's
become vacant interpretations anyway
believes that things exist in a
[Music]